Howells family. Howells family papers (MS Am 1784-1784.13): Guide.
Howells family papers,
- I. bMS Am 1784-1784.4: William Dean Howells collection
  - B. bMS Am 1784.1: Letters from William Dean Howells
    - 2. Letters from William Dean Howells (gift)
      - Howells, Mary (Dean), addressee. 25 letters; 1859-[1872]., (73)
        No. 13 with note from Elinor Gertrude (Mead) Howells to Mary (Dean) Howells; no. 15 with note to Victoria Mellor Howells.
        Nos. 9, 12, 14 and 18 are typed copies. Nos. 1-3, 7, 11, 13, 17, 19, 22 and 24 with typed copies.
        800.20
      - Howells, Mildred, 1872-, addressee. 3 letters; 1877-1917., (74)
        No. 1 with a typed copy; with no. 3 is a typed copy of William Dean Howells' will and a typed copy of John Mead Howells' report as executor of the estate.
      - Howells, Mildred, 1872-, addressee. 251 letters; 1894-1919., (75)
        These are typed copies; originals catalogued as bMS Am 1251. For details see accessions records for 1951-1952 under *51M-236.
      - Howells, Samuel Dean, addressee. 3 letters; 1864., (76)
        No. 1 with typed copy.
      - Howells, Victoria Mellor, addressee. 51 letters; 1857-1890 [n.d.]., (77)
        No. 6 with letter from William Dean Howells to John [Butler Howells].
        Nos. 24 and 27 also addressed to Annie (Howells) Fréchette.
        No. 37 also addressed to Henry [Israel Howells].
        Many with typed copies; nos. 7, 9, 32-36, 39, 42, 45, 50 and 51 are copies only.
      - Howells, William Cooper, 1807-1895, addressee. 778 letters; 1857-1895 [n.d.]., (78)
        Many with typed copies. Nos. 3, 7, 34, 52, 63, 66, 79, 80, 85, 87, 89, 95-97, 100-104, 106, 111, 155, 158, 162-163, 174, 193, 217, 252, 257, 269, 283-284, 292, 299, 313, 315, 317, 328-329, 334, 348-349, 353, 365, 388, 583, 778 are copies only.
        Nos. 6, 11, 12, 14-16, 34 and 66 also addressed to Mary Dean Howells.
        No. 14 with note by Henry C. Howells.
        No. 30 in the hand of Elinor Gertrude (Mead) Howells.
        No. 35 incomplete.
        Nos. 37 and 109 with letter from Elinor Gertrude (Mead) Howells to Victoria Mellor Howells.
        No. 55 with note from Elinor Gertrude (Mead) Howells to William Cooper Howells.
        No. 359 with letter from Victoria M. Howells to Annie (Howells) Fréchette.
        No. 451 with letter from E.W. Durnford King to William Dean Howells.
        No. 652 with letter from Prosper Bender to William Dean Howells.
      - Howells, Winifred, 1864-1889, addressee. 2 letters; 1876-1886., (79)
      - Hurd, Melancthon M., addressee. 1 letter; 1869., (80)
      - James, Henry, 1843-1916, addressee. 1 letter; 1873., (81)
      - Jewett, Sarah Orne, 1849-1909, addressee. 1 letter; 1903., (82)
      - Kilmer, Joyce, 1886-1918, addressee. 1 letter; 1915., (83)
      - Liveright, Horace Brisbin, 1886-1933, addressee. 1 letter; 1913., (84)
        Draft of a telegram in the hand of Mildred Howells.
      - Lloyd, Henry Demarest, 1847-1903, addressee. 2 letters; 1894-1898., (85)
      - Matthews, Brander, 1852-1909, addressee. 3 letters; 1898-1900., (86)
        1-2: *55M-16
        3: *58M-18
      - Norton, Charles Eliot, 1827-1908, addressee. 1 letter; 1879., (87)
      - Popenoe, Perry D., addressee. 1 letter; 1913., (88)
      - Potter, M.D., addressee. 1 letter; 1858., (89)
        *45M-506
      - Pyle, Howard, 1853-1911, addressee. 2 letters; 1900., (90)
      - Rogers, W.K., addressee. 1 letter; 1877., (90a)
      - Sabine, Lillian, addressee. 1 letter; 1919., (91)
        *59M-2
      - Scudder, Horace Elisha, 1838-1902, addressee. 61 letters; 1868-1891., (92)
      - Smalley, Evelyn Garnaut, addressee. 1 letter; 1903., (93)
      - [Smith, Ellen], addressee. 1 letter; 1858., (94)
      - Stevenson, Robert Louis, 1850-1894, addressee. 1 letter; 1893., (95)
      - Ticknor, [], addressee. 2 letters; 1875-1876., (96)
      - Trevelyan, Sir George Otto, bart., 1838-1928, addressee. 1 letter; 1905., (97)
        Copy in an unidentified hand.
      - [Trübner, firm, publishers, London], addressee. 1 letter; 1864., (98)
      - Warner, Charles Dudley, 1829-1900, addressee. 3 letters; 1876-1882., (99)
      - Wendell, Barrett, 1855-1921, addressee. 2 letters; 1914., (100)
        Drafts with typed copies.
        Copy of no. 1 with a note from Edith (Greenough) Wendell to Mildred Howells [n.d.].
      - Whitlock, Brand, 1869-1934, addressee. 1 letter; 1901., (101)
      - [Whitmore, John], addressee. 1 letter; 1885., (102)
        Draft, with copy in the hand of Mildred Howells.
      - Wormwood, R.F., addressee. 1 letter; 1916., (103)
      - Wyatt, Edith Franklin, 1873-1958, addressee. 1 letter; 1906., (104)
  - C. bMS Am 1784.2: Compositions of William Dean Howell
    - 1. Poetry
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. "About the middle of the month of June..." A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (1); 34s.(34p.)
        Lacks stanzas 32-35.
        Stanzas 13-31 are in the hand of Elinor Gertrude (Mead) Howells.
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. "All day long their scythes were twinkling..." Galley proof; [n.p., n.d.], (2); 1s.(1p.)
        With autograph corrections.
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. At fifteen years. A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (3); 2s.(2p.)
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. Battle of the cats. A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (4); 2s.(2p.)
        With face copy and carbon copy of modern typescript.
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. BoPeep: a pastoral. A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (5); 3s.(3p.)
        Stanzas 18-28 first printed in The Atlantic almanac, (Boston, 1870).
        This poem was included by Howells in his letter to Oliver Wendell Holmes, 25 Nov. 1860.
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. City and country. A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (6); 2s.(2p.)
        No. 7 removed from this series.
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. The dream. A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (8); 1s.(2p.)
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. The first cricket. A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (9); 1s.(2p.)
        First printed in Atlantic monthly, Sep. 1869, XXIV, 351.
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. "Full often have I bidden friends farewell..." A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (10); 3s. (3p.)
        With second draft, lacking stanzas 1-6. [n.p., n.d.] 3s. (3p.)
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. The ghosts. A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (11); 2s. (2p.)
        Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. How goes it with you? See "Wie geht es, heut?", no. 30 in this series.
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. "I look out from my window..." A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (12); 2s. (2p.)
        With second draft, [n.p., n.d.] 2s. (2p.)
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. "In among the melancholy waltzers..." A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (13); 1s. (2p.)
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. In the Fall. A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (14); 3s. (3p.)
        Parts 1 and 2 only.
        With a later complete draft, [n.p., n.d.] 6s. (6p.), a modern typed transcript (with carbon copy) and a copy in the hand of Mildred Howells.
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. "I slept one day..." A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (15); 1s. (1p.)
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. Kansas song. MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (16); 2s. (3p.)
        With note from J[oseph] A[lexander] H[owells] to Harvey [Green].
        In an unidentified hand.
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. "Lapsing sleepward from thought to thought..." A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (17); 2s. (2p.)
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. Legend of the college. A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (18); 8s. (8p.)
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. Lost beliefs. A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (19); 1s. (1p.)
        First printed in Atlantic monthly, April, 1860, V, 486.
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. "Mellow the morning sunlight of October..." A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (20); 2s. (2p.)
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. "Not here, where that quick, subtle spirit..." A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (21); 1s. (1p.)
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. "Oh! who art thou, that with such majesty..." A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (22); 1s. (1p.)
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. Ordeals. A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (23); 14s. (19p.)
        With face copy and carbon copy of modern typed transcript.
        TS: *59M-2
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. "Our hopes are balanced by our fears..." A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (24); 1s. (2p.)
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. The passion of the centaur. A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (25); 1s. (3p.)
        With later draft, 1s. (2p.)
        With modern typed copy.
        *58M-7
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. Perdition. A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (26); 1s. (1p.)
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. Tidings. A.MS. (signed); [n.p., n.d.], (27); 1s. (1p.)
        With contemporary typescript.
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. "What is it makes my hand..." A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (28); 1s. (2p.)
        With two later drafts and with face copy and carbon copy of modern typed transcript.
        TS: *63M-16
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. "We were reading one day for our pastime..." A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (29); 1s. (1p.)
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. Wie geht es, heut? A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (30); 2s. (2p.)
        With later draft titled "How goes it with you?" 2s. (2p.)
    - 2. Prose
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. A case in point. A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (31); 27s.(27p.)
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. The children of the summer. T.S. and A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (32); 139s.(140p.)
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. Coast of Bohemia and Story of a [play]. Galley proofs; [n.p., n.d.], (32b); 7s.(16p.)
        With galley proofs of Heroines of fiction, The shadow of a dream, Son of Royal Langbraith, A Traveler from Altruria, Through the eye, etc..
        A series of prefaces (not published) for Harper's Library Edition of The Writings of William Dean Howells (ca. 1910-1911 ).
        First published by George Arms, "Howells' unpublished prefaces," New England Quarterly (Dec 1944).
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. Connelly's uncle. A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (33); 4s(4p.)
        Outline of a comedy, never written, sent to Henry Mills Alden.
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. [Coonrod Dryfoos]. TS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (34); 8s.(8p.)
        With autograph corrections and with face copy and carbon copy of modern typed transcript.
        Unfinished story about Pennsylvania emigrants to Ohio; possible an early sketch for the character Coonrod Dryfoos in A hazard of new fortunes.
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. Dulldale. A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (35); 6s.(6p.)
        With face copy and carbon copy of modern transcript.
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. [The easy chair. The letters of Mark Twain, ed. by Albert Bigelow Paine.] TS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (36); 8s.(8p.)
        *45M-509
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. [Geoffrey Winter]. A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (37); 189s.(190p.)
        William Dean Howells' first attempt at the novel; Chap. I publ. in Knickerbacker, Aug 1861 as short story entitled "A dream".
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. [The ghost-maker]. A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (38); 46s.(46p.)
        Lacks pages 1, 2, 30-37, 53-55. There is no p.18 and two pages are numbered 56.
        p.22-29 are in the hand of Elinor Gertrude (Mead) Howells.
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920.; [Heinrich Heine: Der Romantische Schule]. A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (39); 1s.(1p.)
        Fragment.
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. [The heroic history of Venice]. TS. (unsigned); [n.p., 26 Oct. 1899], (40)
        Outline for a proposed series of papers on Venice.
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. The home-towners [or, Incident of convalescence]. TS. and A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (41); 44s.(44p.)
        Two pages are numbered 14, three pages are numbered 25.
        The first 19 1/2 p. are TS. with autograph revisions; the rest is A.MS. With this are the face copy and carbon copy of a typed transcript.
        Unpublished; Howells' last (unfinished) novel.
        *48M-228F
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. A love match. A.MS. and TS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (42); 142s.(145p.)
        With autograph revisions.
        Unfinished.
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. [Luke Beazeley]. A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (43); 42s.(42p.)
        Unfinished story, possibly written in the 1870 's.
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. [Notes for a speech honoring Tommaso Salvini]. A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (44); 1s.(2p.)
        800-20
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. [Notes on Italian poets.] A.MSS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (45); 12s.(12p.)
        Fragments.
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. [Notes on the theatre]. A.MS. and MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (46); 5s.(5p.)
        Part in the hand of Elinor Gertrude (Mead) Howells.
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. Old clothes. A.MS. (signed); [n.p., n.d.]., (47); 6s.(6p.)
        With the face copy and carbon copy of modern transcript.
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. The prisoner of prosperity. A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.]., (48); 22s.(22p.)
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. [The quality of mercy; a synopsis] TS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.]., (49); 3s.(3p.)
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. Questions noted down to put to Mr. Roswell Smith, in expectation of a conditional offer from him... A.MS. (unsigned); [Boston] 11 May 1885., (50); 1s.(2p.)
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. The real diary of a boy. TS. and A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.]., (51); 30s.(30p.)
        The first 19 pages are TS. with autograph revisions, the rest is A.MS.
        Unpublished.
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. The rise of Silas Lapham [a play, in collaboration with Paul Kester] 4 TSS., as follows:, (52)
        (1) TS. with revisions by Howells; an early draft. 193s.(214p.)
        (2) TS. with revisions by Howells. 150s.(150p.)
        (3) TS. (acting copy) with corrections. 85s.(85p.)
        (4) TS. (another acting copy) with revisions by Howells and another (Paul Kester?).
        Permission to publish must be secured from Howells family and heirs of Paul Kester, c/o Mr. P. S. Griffiths, Montrose, Westmoreland County, Virginia.
        *48M-229
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. Summer resorts. A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.]., (53); 9s.(9p.)
        Lacks p.7.
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. A sea-change [or Love's stowaway], (53a)
        See bMS Am 1784.12 (65-66)
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. The world of fiction: a magazine of imaginative literature. A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (54); 2s.(2p.)
        With modern typed transcript.
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. Years of my middle life. A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (55); 1s.(2p.)
        Notes made for a continuation of Years of my youth.
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. [Collection of galley-proofs and cuttings of articles by W.D.H.; v.p.] 1860., (56); 12s.(12p.)
        Contents: "Letters from the country I. June 30, 1860, " Ohio State weekly journal, 10 Jul. 1860 (L,1); "Letters en passant", (Buffalo, July 17); Ohio state journal, 23 Jul. 1860 (XXIV,1); "En passant", (Niagara Falls, 19 Jul. 1860 ), ibid., 24 Jul. 1860; [Letter, Montreal, L.C., July 22, 1860 ]; "En passant" [Quebec, July 26], Ohio state journal, 4 Aug. 1860 (XXIV,1); "En passant" [Portland, July 29], ibid., 6 Aug. 1860; 2 proofs of "En passant" [Boston, 1 Aug. 1860 ] 1 from ibid., 7 Aug. 1860 (XXIV,1), and the Cincinnati Gazette. Also "The Boots," signed "Octavius Augustus Jones", from The daily gazette, Cincinnati [n.p., n.d.].
        *45M-513
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. [Galley-proofs; n.p., n.d.], (57); 6s.(6p.)
        Two sets of proofs for an unidentified article.
  - D. bMS Am 1784.3: Diaries and other papers
    - 1. Diaries and journals
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. [Diary, 1850; Spanish exercises, 1852-1857]. A.MS. (signed); Columbus and Ashtabula, Ohio, [1850-1857], (1); 1v.
        *45M-502
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. A.MS. notebook; Columbus, Ohio; 20 Mar. 1857-1858 24 Aug., (2); 1v.
        *45M-354
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. A.MS. diary and account book; Jefferson, Ohio; 1861., (3); 1v.
        *45M-355
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. A.MS. diary; Venice, 1861-1862., (4); 72s.(72p.)
        *45M-503
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. A.MS. journal and notebook. [Cambridge, Mass.] 1869., (5); 1v.
        With face copy and carbon copy of a modern typescript.
        Includes notes made in preparation for A foregone conclusion.
        *45M-504
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. 25 A.MS. travel diaries; [v.p.] 1864-1918., (6); 25 v.
        no.22: *55M-16
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. A.MS. notebook; [n.p., n.d.], (7); 1v.
        Contains sketches and notes for a number of the novels, including The rise of Silas Lapham.
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. From Folkestone to London; May 15, 1904. TS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (8); 9s.(9p.)
    - 2. Business and other papers
      Includes photographs.
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. [Contracts for works no longer in copyright]., (9); 53 items.
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. [Contracts for works still (1966) in copyright]., (10); 15 items.
        Note: This category on deposit only until expiration of copyright, when they are to become a gift to Harvard.
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. [Family business papers, will of William Cooper Howells, etc.], (11); 3 folders.
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. [Investments and miscellaneous], (12); 1 folder.
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. [Papers relating to cooperative apartment at 130 W. 57th Street, New York.], (13); 2 folders.
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. [Insurance on property at York Harbour, Maine], (14); 1 folder.
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. [Papers concerning real estate], (15); 1 folder.
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. [Life insurance papers], (16); 2 folders.
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. [Check books and bank books], (17); 10 items.
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. [Statement of expenses for lecture tour]. TS. (unsigned); [n.p., ca. 1897], (18); 1s.(1p.)
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. [2 lists for the `Library Edition' of the works of W.D.H., published by Harper and Brothers]. TS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (19); 7s.(7p.)
        The second list with two carbon copies.
      - Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920. [Scrapbooks containing newspaper clippings. v.p., v.d.], (20); 5 v.
        With no. 5 is a review of A little girl among the old masters.
      - Clemens, Samuel Langhorne, 1835-1910. [Collection of printed material concerning Mark Twain's 70th birthday; v.p.] 1905., (21); 1 folder.
      - American academy of arts and letters. New York. [Miscellaneous publications, newspaper clippings, etc., relating to the centennial celebration of the Academy for Howells, v.p.] 1937., (22); 1 folder.
        Many of the clippings are brittle and crumbling. *43M-788F
      - Newspaper clippings concerning the Chicago anarchists., (23); 1 folder.
        for letter see bMSAm 1784.1(28+39)
      - Miscellaneous printed material., (24); 3 boxes.
      - Miscellaneous printed material, including honorary degrees., (25)
      - Photographs., (26); 1 box.
      - Jackson, Esther. Autograph manuscript letter (signed) to Miss Howells; Peterborough, New Hampshire, 1954 January 24., (26a); 1 folder.
        Letter concerns text by William Dean Howells from a tablet at Holy Trinity Church, Goodram Gate, York, England and an account of The Snow Angel. Also with transcript of letter.
        No accession number. Found with: MS Storage 281. Collection materials assembled by Carolyn Jakeman.
- II. bMS Am 1784.4: Tributes to William Dean Howells on the occasion of his 80th birthday.
  Compiled by the Joint committee on the literary arts.
  Morocco-bound album with mounted manuscript letters from fellow writers.
  *43M-800F
  - Adams, Brooks, 1848-1927. 1 letter to Hamlin Garland; 1917., (1); (p.3)
  - Adams, Samuel Hopkins, 1871-1958. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (2); (p.4)
  - Ade, George, 1866-1944. 1 letter to William Dean Howells; 1917., (3); (p.5)
  - Alden, Henry Mills, 1836-1919. 1 letter to William Dean Howells; 1917., (4); (p.7)
  - Aldrich, Richard, 1863-1937. 1 letter to Hamlin Garland; 1917., (5); (p.6)
  - Allen, James Lane, 1849-1925. 1 letter to William Dean Howells; 1917., (6); (p.9)
  - Austin, Mary (Hunter) 1868-1934. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (7); (p.8)
  - Baker, Ray Stannard, 1870-1946. 1 letter to William Dean Howells; 1917., (8); (p.19)
  - Baldwin, Simeon Eben, 1840-1927. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (9); (p.10)
  - Beckwith, James Carroll, 1852-1917. 1 letter to William Dean Howells; 1917., (10); (p.11)
  - Bennett, Arnold, 1867-1931. 1 letter to Hamlin Garland; 1917., (11); (p.22)
  - Blashfield, Edwin Howland, 1848-1936. 2 letters to Hamlin Garland; 1917., (12); (p.12-13)
  - Bok, Edward William, 1863-1930. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (13); (p.14)
  - Bowker, Richard Rogers, 1848-1933. 1 letter to the Joint Committee of the Literary Arts; 1917., (14); (p.15)
  - Bradford, Gamaliel, 1863-1932. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (15); (p.16)
  - Bryce, James Bryce, viscount, 1838-1922. 1 letter to Hamlin Garland; 1917., (16); (p.21)
  - Burnett, Frances (Hodgson) 1849-1924. 1 letter to William Dean Howells; 1917., (17); (p.20)
  - Burton, Richard, 1861-1940. 1 letter to William Dean Howells; 1917., (18); (p.17)
  - Butler, Ellis Parker, 1869-1937. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (19); (p.18)
  - Cable, George Washington, 1844-1925. 1 letter to Hamlin Garland; 1917., (20); (p.24)
  - Chamberlin, Joseph Edgar, 1851-1935. 1 letter to Hamlin Garland; 1917., (21); (p.31-33)
  - Channing, Edward, 1856-1931. 1 letter to Hamlin Garland; 1917., (22); (p.25)
  - Chatfield-Taylor, Hobart Chatfield, 1865-1945. 1 letter to Hamlin Garland; 1917., (23); (p.118)
  - Cheney, John Vance, 1848-1922. 1 letter to Hamlin Garland; 1917., (24); (p.26)
  - Churchill, Winston, 1871-1947. 1 letter to Hamlin Garland; 1917., (25); (p.27)
  - Cobb, Irvin Shrewsbury, 1876-1944. 1 letter to Hamlin Garland; 1917., (26); (p.28)
  - Cox, Kenyon, 1856-1919. 1 letter to Hamlin Garland; 1917., (27); (p.29)
  - Cross, Wilbur Lucius, 1862-1948. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (28); (p.30)
  - Deland, Margaret (Campbell) 1857-1944. 1 letter to William Dean Howells; 1917., (29); (p.34)
  - Eaton, Walter Prichard, 1878-. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (30); (p.35)
  - Eliot, Charles William, 1834-1926. 1 letter to Edward J. Wheeler; 1917., (31); (p.36)
  - Evans, Florence (Wilkinson). 1 letter to William Dean Howells; 1917., (32); (p.127)
  - Field, Roswell Martin, 1851-1919. 1 letter to William Dean Howells; 1917., (33); (p.41)
  - Fox, John, 1862-1919. 1 letter to Hamlin Garland; 1917., (34); (p.37)
  - Freeman, Mary Eleanor (Wilkins) 1862-1930. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (35); (p.38)
  - French, Daniel Chester, 1850-1931. 1 letter to Hamlin Garland; 1917., (36); (p.39)
  - Furness, Horace Howard, 1865-1930. 1 letter to William Dean Howells; 1917., (37); (p.40)
  - Garland, Hamlin, 1860-1940. Tribute to William Dean Howells; 1917., (38); (p.1-2)